<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-02-27T20:15:32+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Impossible Robotics</title><subtitle>Impossible Robotics is an FRC team (team 5412) located in the North of the Netherlands. Visit our site for the latest news and information about our team!</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Building day!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020-02-17/building-day/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Building day!" /><published>2020-02-17T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-02-17T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020-02-17/building-day</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020-02-17/building-day/">&lt;p&gt;Today we continued working on our robot at the building space of our main sponsor &lt;a href=&quot;victronenergy.nl&quot;&gt;Victron Energy&lt;/a&gt;. After waiting a very long time for our meccanum wheels we decided it probably was the best idea to first assemble the drive train with traction and omniwheels. We also rewired all the cables so now all the cables look a lot better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We really want to thank &lt;a href=&quot;victronenergy.nl&quot;&gt;Victron Energy&lt;/a&gt; for their hospitality, for using the building space and all the other support!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/res/posts/2020-02-17-building-day/working.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;photo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Aron Hoekstra and Stefan Sijbesma</name></author><summary type="html">Today we continued working on our robot at the building space of our main sponsor Victron Energy. After waiting a very long time for our meccanum wheels we decided it probably was the best idea to first assemble the drive train with traction and omniwheels. We also rewired all the cables so now all the cables look a lot better.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Chairmans Essay</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020-02-12/chairmans-essay/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chairmans Essay" /><published>2020-02-12T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-02-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020-02-12/chairmans-essay</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020-02-12/chairmans-essay/">&lt;p&gt;Over the last few weeks we have worked on our Chairman’s essay. Chairman’s is one of the most prestigious awards in the FIRST Robotics Competition, it honors the team that best represents a model for other teams to emulate and best embodies the mission of FIRST. To participate in Chairman’s a team has to write an essay, make a video and give a presentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;/res/posts/2020-02-15-chairmans-essay/chairmans.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;our essay&lt;/a&gt; you can read about our efforts to spread FIRST in the netherlands and the impact we have had on our community. We will continue working on the other aspects of Chairman’s and are excited to share more in the future.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Pieter Venderbos</name></author><summary type="html">Over the last few weeks we have worked on our Chairman’s essay. Chairman’s is one of the most prestigious awards in the FIRST Robotics Competition, it honors the team that best represents a model for other teams to emulate and best embodies the mission of FIRST. To participate in Chairman’s a team has to write an essay, make a video and give a presentation.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">FIRST Lego League Benelux Final</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020-01-25/benelux-finale/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="FIRST Lego League Benelux Final" /><published>2020-01-25T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-01-25T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020-01-25/benelux-finale</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020-01-25/benelux-finale/">&lt;p&gt;Last week we were invited for the annual Benelux final of the FIRST Lego League, which was held in Breda this year. This is the final where the best 53 teams from Belgium, The Netherlands and Luxembourg present their innovation project and compete at the playing field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This day we were present at the science festival, where we demonstrated what it is like to be in the FIRST Robotics Competition. The guests were able to drive our robot from last year. Besides that we were building the robot for this years challenge, the visitors could walk by and see what we were doing. The science festival was well attended, so there were lots of people who came by.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/res/posts/2020-01-25-benelux-finale/working.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;photo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our team members, Henk van der Wal and Jamie Kazemier have helped with judging the FLL teams this day. Henk was part of the judging panel for the innovation project, while Jamie was part of the child judges, he learned a lot from this experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned above, we were also building our robot this day. Our focus was on the arm we are going to use to climb on the generator switch. It didn’t work out as well as we hoped it would do, because beforehand we forgot to account for a few things. So we went on prototyping, to solve the problems. We were not able to finish it entirely, so we will go on next time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video width=&quot;320&quot; controls=&quot;&quot;&gt;
   &lt;source src=&quot;/res/posts/2020-01-25-benelux-finale/video.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
   Video is not supported by your browser
&lt;/video&gt;</content><author><name>Sytse de Boer and Pieter Venderbos</name></author><summary type="html">Last week we were invited for the annual Benelux final of the FIRST Lego League, which was held in Breda this year. This is the final where the best 53 teams from Belgium, The Netherlands and Luxembourg present their innovation project and compete at the playing field.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Week 1 robot progress</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020-01-11/building-robot/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Week 1 robot progress" /><published>2020-01-11T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-01-11T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020-01-11/building-robot</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020-01-11/building-robot/">&lt;p&gt;Today we continued  building and designing our robot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started by watching inspiring videos from “Robot in three days” where we got some inspiration for our creation. Later we went on making a part of our drive train, including assembling the gearboxes and the mecanum wheels. Assembling the mecanum wheels took more time than expected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also built prototypes for the climbing mechanism. We had fun ideas, we decided on making a spring loaded arm wich can be moved back in with a rope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion we couldn’t do everything we hoped to do but the base of our creation has been layed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/res/posts/2020-01-11-robot-progress-week-1/working.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;robot-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sytse de Boer en Tom Dunant Maurits</name></author><summary type="html">Today we continued building and designing our robot.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">FRC Kick-Off</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020-01-04/frc-kickoff/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="FRC Kick-Off" /><published>2020-01-04T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-01-04T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020-01-04/frc-kickoff</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020-01-04/frc-kickoff/">&lt;p&gt;On this Saturday we had our annual Kick-off event. During the event FIRST revealed this year’s FIRST
Robotics Competition Infinite Recharge. We came together with our team to watch the reveal and
discuss our strategy for the coming season. Over the next 6 weeks different we will work together to
overcome challenges while building a robot that can accurately shoot balls, balance a switch by
hanging on it and rotate a panel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are excited to show you more in the coming weeks and hope you will follow along as we share
more of our journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find a brief explanation of this year’s challenge in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gmiYWTmFRVE&amp;amp;amp=&amp;amp;feature=emb_title&quot;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt; and for those looking for a
more in depth look there is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://firstfrc.blob.core.windows.net/frc2020/Manual/2020FRCGameSeasonManual.pdf&quot;&gt;game manual&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/res/posts/2020-01-04-frc-kickoff/photo1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;team-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Pieter Venderbos</name></author><summary type="html">On this Saturday we had our annual Kick-off event. During the event FIRST revealed this year’s FIRST Robotics Competition Infinite Recharge. We came together with our team to watch the reveal and discuss our strategy for the coming season. Over the next 6 weeks different we will work together to overcome challenges while building a robot that can accurately shoot balls, balance a switch by hanging on it and rotate a panel.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">FIRST Lego League Regional</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019-11-30/fll-regional/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="FIRST Lego League Regional" /><published>2019-11-30T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-11-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019-11-30/fll-regional</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019-11-30/fll-regional/">&lt;p&gt;At the FLL regional are a lot of children from primary and middle school, the contestants are aged 9 to 14. In the Netherlands a lot of FLL teams don’t know that there are other FIRST programs so for them it ends by the FIRST Lego League.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We would really like that this would change so that’s why we promote FRC at different FLL regionals in the Netherlands. At this event there was also a FTC team called &lt;a href=&quot;http://prettysmartrobotics.nl&quot;&gt;Pretty Smart Robotics&lt;/a&gt;. So at this event there were a lot of different teams from different FIRST programs and we think that’s really cool!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/res/posts/2019-11-30-fll-regional/photo1.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;photo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides the fact we told people about FRC we also helped the organisation of the regional with judging and packing after the event!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Stefan Sijbesma</name></author><summary type="html">At the FLL regional are a lot of children from primary and middle school, the contestants are aged 9 to 14. In the Netherlands a lot of FLL teams don’t know that there are other FIRST programs so for them it ends by the FIRST Lego League.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Getting to know technology: Techniek Tastbaar</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019-11-28/techniek-tastbaar/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Getting to know technology: Techniek Tastbaar" /><published>2019-11-28T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-11-28T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019-11-28/techniek-tastbaar</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019-11-28/techniek-tastbaar/">&lt;p&gt;In the past month, our team has not been busy with any competitions. Instead, we have been working on getting publicity. Nope, not for our team, but for technology in general. And that is why we’ve been helping at Techniek Tastbaar in our province Friesland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Techniek Tastbaar is an event for children aged 10 to 16, where they can have a first glimpse of technology in the grown-up world. They get lots of information from all kinds of different businessess, about jobs and career oppurtunities, but the most important goal of the event is to make these children enthusiastic about thechnology. After all, thechnology is the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many kinds of different professions are presented: from the army, to the truck drivers, from the painters to the carpenters and from the welders to the mechanics. And of course, there is us, the Robotics team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were there to let children meet with our side of technology. To show that technology can be more than for example being a mechanic, or sitting at a desk all day, working behind a computer. It can also be working in a team to accomplish goals, building a robot and competing in competitions! We brought some of our robots: &lt;em&gt;Armstrong&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Victor&lt;/em&gt; and our newest First Global robot. Certainly everyone could try them out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was very enjoyable, showing everyone what we’re doing and especially teaching them a bit about how some of our robots work. Hopefully we have shown that there are multiple sides of technology and that it can be a lot of fun!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Allison Han van der Spoel</name></author><summary type="html">In the past month, our team has not been busy with any competitions. Instead, we have been working on getting publicity. Nope, not for our team, but for technology in general. And that is why we’ve been helping at Techniek Tastbaar in our province Friesland.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">We have arrived in Dubai!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019-10-24/arrived-in-dubai/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="We have arrived in Dubai!" /><published>2019-10-24T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-10-24T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019-10-24/arrived-in-dubai</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019-10-24/arrived-in-dubai/">&lt;p&gt;After a few weeks of hard work on our FGC robot, we finally were ready to pack and travel to Dubai for the competitions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/res/posts/2019-10-24-arrived-in-dubai/team.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;arrived-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the last few weeks we have been working on our robot in the garage of a student of ours. When the kit of parts arrived we were really exited to see what we got this year (click &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/B3boZ0Shtkn/?utm_source=ig_web_copy_link&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for a video)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some time we came up with a few ideas for the robot, and we started experimenting with some of them. Eventually we sticked to the idea of an expandable arm that could carry balls to the highest level of the centerpiece.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/res/posts/2019-10-24-arrived-in-dubai/robot.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;robot-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope to meet some great new teams, and wish everyone the best of luck!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Bauke Westendorp</name></author><summary type="html">After a few weeks of hard work on our FGC robot, we finally were ready to pack and travel to Dubai for the competitions.</summary></entry></feed>