<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-10-22T20:41:33+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Impossible Robotics</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">FRC Kickoff</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019-04-12/frc-kickoff/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="FRC Kickoff" /><published>2019-04-12T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-04-12T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019-04-12/frc-kickoff</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019-04-12/frc-kickoff/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/res/posts/2019-10-22-frc-kickoff/t1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;team-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On fifth and sixth of January we had our annual kick-off event. Like the last few years, we did this event in the Doe Museum in Veendam. During this event the FIRST Robotics Competition officially started. A live stream was held, on which this years challenge is revealed to all the participating teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the first day of the event we focused on discussing the different options for our robot and strategizing our plan for the challenge. We looked at all the different challenge we could encounter during the competition and choose the most effective solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second day we continued to explore our options we choose for the robot. We prepared everything for the coming weeks, so we can start working right away. During the second day we also did demonstrations with our robots for the kids at the museum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are excited for the upcoming weeks and wish all the other teams the best of luck for the Destination: Deep Space season.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Bauke Westendorp</name></author><category term="frc" /><category term="kickoff" /><category term="frc kickoff" /><category term="new season" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Last Days of Competition</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019-04-08/last-days-of-competition/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Last Days of Competition" /><published>2019-04-08T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-04-08T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019-04-08/last-days-of-competition</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019-04-08/last-days-of-competition/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/res/posts/2019-10-22-last-days-of-competition/20180818_140104.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;team-image-1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On day 5 and 6 we played our last six qualification matches. Before every round, we resolved issues with software and mechanical on our robot. In our last qualification match, our robot worked perfectly. We did not make it to the playoffs, but we had the best of times. We even got to meet Woodie Flowers and his wife at our pit. The best part was reserved for last. We received the first place award for International Enthusiasm. We are very happy with the award and we are very grateful that we had the chance to represent the Netherlands ones again in this year’s competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/res/posts/2019-10-22-last-days-of-competition/20180817_123322.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;match&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/res/posts/2019-10-22-last-days-of-competition/20180817_163248.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;consultation&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/res/posts/2019-10-22-last-days-of-competition/20180818_124438.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;team-image-2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Bauke Westendorp</name></author><category term="competition" /><category term="last days" /><category term="fgc" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New Website</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019-01-22/new-website/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Website" /><published>2019-01-22T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-01-22T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019-01-22/new-website</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019-01-22/new-website/">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to our new website! We decided that our old website wasn’t good enough anymore, so we build a completely new website from scratch. Here you can find lot’s of information about our team. In the future we will add more pages and continue to update the website. We hope you like it so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/res/posts/2019-10-22-new-website/Reveal_Doe_Museum_Veendam-29.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;team-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Impossible Robotics is a non-profit organization that participates in the FIRST Robotics Competition. We also participate in numerous other events. Our team (team 5412) is composed of High School and College students and is mainly located in the North of the Netherlands. For more information about our team click &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.impossible-robotics.com/about-us/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our team aims to inspire and enthuse everyone for technology, from kids, to teenagers and adults. We also try to forge a link between schools and employers.  Besides that we want to promote STEM around the world. For more information about our goals and vision click &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.impossible-robotics.com/dev/our-vision/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FIRST is an American organization that took upon itself the task to promote technology worldwide. To achieve this goal, First, among other things, organizes multiple competitions, including the FIRST Robotics Competition. For more information about FIRST or the FRC click &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.impossible-robotics.com/dev/what-are-first-frc/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Bauke Westendorp</name></author><category term="new website" /><category term="new" /><category term="website" /><summary type="html">Welcome to our new website! We decided that our old website wasn’t good enough anymore, so we build a completely new website from scratch. Here you can find lot’s of information about our team. In the future we will add more pages and continue to update the website. We hope you like it so far.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">On Our Way To Mexico</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018-10-31/on-our-way-to-mexico/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On Our Way To Mexico" /><published>2018-10-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-10-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018-10-31/on-our-way-to-mexico</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018-10-31/on-our-way-to-mexico/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/res/posts/2019-10-22-on-our-way-to-mexico/20180813_142351.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;airport-image-1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this year’s FIRST Global Challenge starting in just two days we went on our way early in the morning to catch our flight to Mexico city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/res/posts/2019-10-22-on-our-way-to-mexico/20180812_173153.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;crate&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/res/posts/2019-10-22-on-our-way-to-mexico/20180813_071814.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;luggage&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly, our flight had to be canceled because of technical issues. We ended up spending most of the day waiting at the airport before being able to go to a hotel and get some sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/res/posts/2019-10-22-on-our-way-to-mexico/20180813_155854.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;airport-image-2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, we will be able to fly to Mexico tomorrow and we should arrive on time for the competition. We are looking forward to meeting all the other teams there and wish everyone the best of luck in the upcoming games.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Bauke Westendorp</name></author><category term="mexico" /><category term="on our way" /><category term="fgc" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>